Jason Aviles, Software Engineer

5515560079, jason.aviles.03@gmail.com

LINKS	GitHub, Linkedin	
PROFILE	I started off as a Walmart employee with a dream. I grow up interested in soft development, but didn't think it would be a reality for me. Fast forward, through hard work and dedication I am a full stack software engineer, project manager within the tech field and entrepreneur.	
SKILLS	Javascript ES6	Git(Git Flow)
	CSS / SASS / LESS	Github
	HTML5	React / Redux
	REST / MySQL	Wireframing

PROJECTS

Sep 2019 — Oct 2019

sauti-databank

remotly

Informal cross-border trade is a major feature of African economies: it creates jobs, contributes to food and energy security, and alleviates poverty. However many traders are unaware of their rights, required customs procedures and documentation, making them vulnerable to corruption and harassment.

website link: https://www.sauti-databank.com/

Technology used

- MySQL for the database
- node/express/knex for the server
- · React for the front-end
- Nivo for the charts
- Trello for the planing
- Github
- Heroku for the back-end deployment
- Netlify for the front-end deployment

Oct 2019 — Present

Food review v.2 FullStack

remotely

Food review v.2 Full-stack hooks people up with delicious local food, allowing them to write a media post of what they ordered, what they rated it, and other information about their dining experience. The basic idea is that restaurant-goers will be able to document their visits, avoid ordering menu items they didn't actually like, and remember things about their order that they wanted to be reminded of in the future. It could also mean ensuring that a restaurant-goer who wants to try absolutely everything on a menu could treat it like a checklist.

web-site.

Front-end: https://upbeat-kare-49e45f.netlify.com

Back-end: https://foodappapisql.herokuapp.com/

Technology used:

Front end-

- · React and React hooks
- Axios
- React-router-dom
- React-Reveal
- Sementic ui
- · Deployed on Netflix

Back end-

- Node/express/knex for the server
- · MySQL for the database
- · Post-man for route checking
- Heroku for deployment

Sep 2019 — Sep 2019 Back-end foodie-fun remotly

The app solves personal hunger problems, keeps people from ordering the same old thing every time they visit a restaurant, maintains a personal guide of what restaurants and what dishes are good.

In addition, the app keeps track of what meals you have ordered and at what restaurants, the wait time you encountered when you ordered, and any additional comments that you might want to remember about your order.

website link

back-end documentation: https://github.com/build-week-foodie-fun/BE

Technology used for back-end

- Post-man
- node/express/knex for server
- SQLite for the database
- Heroku for development

Aug 2019 — Aug 2019

Pokemon cards

remotely

Created a Pokemon cards like admin site after registering and logining you can create read update or delete any card the site also has a search bar and pagination.

website: https://worthymonadmin.netlify.com

Technology used:

Front-end:

- React-Redux
- react-reveal
- axios
- material ui

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Jan 2019 — Present

Freelance Full-stack Developer, self employed

United States

Worked on full stack personal public speaking site for a client

website:jeffaviles.com

Technology used:

- HTML
- CSS/sass
- bootstrap wire-framing
- JavaScript
- PHP

May 2019 — Present

Team Lead, Lambda School

jersey city

I foster a positive learning environment by leading a group of 8 students. My primary role is to guide each students towards success within the program.

.Created and managed master learning plan .Managed end-to-end project delivery

.Developed project plans with resource assignments

.Provided guidance to team and other project managers .Collaborated with participants to determine product timeline

.Oversaw code development of team

Jan 2019 - Present

Relationship / Life Coach, J. Aviles

United States

Experienced life coach with over 2 years of experience partnering with clients, developing positive practices, and offering general guidance. Skilled in counseling clients in issues such as love and relationships, health and wellbeing, and positive living. Previously worked with clients ranging in age from 19 to 30 and implemented

various positive approach principles that were supportively received and recommended for implementation throughout organization.

Jan 2019 — Oct 2019

Freelance Photographer and Website Developer, Media by J. Aviles

United States

Freelance Photographer and Website Developer located in New Jersey but also take assignments all over the United States

- . Retouched images and color corrected to more closely match item to screen
- . Worked directly with small business owners to develop an online presence
- . Developed web sites using WordPress, HTML, CSS, CSS3, Less, Sass and JavaScript
- . Managed digital image database and uploaded images to existing website
- . Set up lights and diffusing filters to adjusting brightness to desired level of lighting

EDUCATION

Mar 2019 — Jan 2020

Full Stack certification, Lambda School Academy

remotely

Lambda School is a 9+ month Computer Science & Software Engineering Academy that provides an immersive hands-on curriculum with a focus on computer science, and full-stack web development. Students in this program...

- .Approach all coding challenges using pair programming.
- .Utilize agile software development and Git workflow on all projects.
- .Gain hands-on experience with client and server testing,
- .Design original user experiences across a range of web and mobile platforms, from idealization, to wire-framing, to final product.
- .Complete all curriculum course work including: React, React Native, Redux, Node, Express, MongoDB, Jest, Python, Django, etc.
- .Write production-ready code using ReactJS, Redux, and CSS on the frontend and NodeJS and Express on the backend to build single page applications.